ABHAY BAKSHI FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Vancouver, BC | abhaybakshi8@gmail.com | 778-992-0637| linkedin.com/in/abhay-bakshi/

CAREER SUMMARY

2 years of experience as a junior front-end developer with 2 companies and several capstone projects. Self-motivated and disciplined Front-End Engineer, augmenting virtual experiences by

combining art & creative programming to build scalable solutions. Independent learner, interested in personal development & curious to learn new tooling & technologies.

Languages

React, React Native, Redux, CSS Preprocessors, Sass, Styled Components, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Next.js, MySQL, Typescript, php, HTML, CSS.

Technology

REST APIs, Firebase, Webpack, NPM, WordPress, WebGL, Browser Extensions.

Tools

Git Hub version control system (GIT), Command Line tools, Visual Studio Code, Atom, Postman, Docker, Figma (UI/UX Design), Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop.

Methodology

Scrum, Pair programming, Agile Development, User Research, Solution Design Research, Kanban, Test Driven Development, User Experience Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Vice President External, BCITSA

May 2021 - Present

- Designed a systematic method of storing half-yearly ridership data from Trans-Link to facilitate decision-making.
- Lobbied and advocated at a provincial and national level, resulting in eradicating interest on student loans in BC.
- Communicated with Senators, Ministers, and MPs of Canada to advocate and encourage action on student concerns.

Developer, Kinder Kampus

August 2021 - December 2021

- Redesigned the website interface to improve responsiveness, a11y standards & provide a seamless user experience using lightweight & high-fidelity prototyping with Figma.
- Customized plugins/bridges with JavaScript to display states in a dynamic way & used php for **server-side rendering**.
- Optimized the website by using asynchronous programming to efficiently parse data being received from APIs

Developer, Young Academics Learning Club

August 2021 - December 2021

- Implemented the principles of UI/UX to build a scalable website and used jQuery to handle form actions & data
- Communicated clearly and concisely with the client to explain complex methodologies in a non-technical manner.
- Utilized a breadth of front-end architecture principles to build a simple and elegant solution for the client.

EXTRA CURRICULAR

Former Volunteer at Van Isle Health Professional Musician National Tennis Player Personal Development Enthusiast Advanced Meditator

SELECTED PROJECT WORK

Lead Developer, Project Manager, Buzzy Bee

- Built algorithms using Object Oriented Programming to receive data using custom designed REST APIs, & architect it for front-end.
- Engineered a sorting algorithm in JavaScript/React Native that compared team schedules to provide availability for collaboration.
- Optimized the application architecture by using asynchronous request handling & promise-based programming.
- Conducted sprint planning, sprint retrospectives alongside pair programming and code reviews to collaborate effectively with peer developers.

Lead Developer, Project Manager, Eco-how

- Orchestrated a responsive web design & fabricated core functionality of the application within a small team.
- Designed & developed a drag & drop sorting game using React and WebGL to enhance the user learning experience.
- Implemented a mobile-first approach to build a responsive website with reusable and accessible front-end components.
- Conducted thorough user testing throughout the software development lifecycle to deliver well documented code.

EDUCATION

BCIT, Digital Design and Development.

September 2020 - March 2022

- · Dean's First Year Leadership Award
- Set Representative Liaison Between program Head and student body

North Island College Post Degree Diploma in Marketing

January 2019 - December 2019

Mats University, Bachelor of Commerce

January 2015 - December 2018

WEBSITE